<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Programming :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:20:44 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to HTML</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/01-introduction/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/01-introduction/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the Hypertext Markup Language. This is a continuation of our previous videos where we talked about the history of the internet, as well as how the internet actually worked. Now, in those videos, we took a look at Sir Tim Berners-Lee, who invented the Hypertext Markup Language along with the web server and the technology that was used to actually serve those web pages. The first version of HTML that Sir Tim Berners-Lee released in 1990, was still a huge improvement over the content that was being served on the Internet at that time. We really had no unify language that we were able to use to distribute information on the web. HTML 1.0 brought that to light. Even though throughout the 90s, HTML was a pretty static language, meaning that our webpages were still pretty straightforward, there really wasn’t a whole lot of dynamic content. It wasn’t until Web 4.0 released and the late 90s and even into the early 2000s, where we started to make the transition to the Web 2.0 era, where we started to see a lot more social media type content, and very dynamic content being hosted on the web, like a lot of media as well. The big landmark version of HTML, HTML 4.0, was really important because this is also where Cascading Style Sheets came into play. Before, we could still style our web pages to a certain extent, but all of those styles were actually built into the page.</description></item><item><title>Basic HTML Part 1</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/02-basic-html-1/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/02-basic-html-1/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to continue our talk on HTML and start looking a little bit at HTML tags. As we mentioned before, the language itself works off of a series of tags, tags are denoted by a less than and greater than symbol with the name of the tag in between. Now, some tags may also actually have attributes in between there, but we’ll get to that later. To make a basic web page, we need four primary tags, HTML, head, and body. But we’ll also add in title there, so we can actually have a name for our webpage as well. The HTML tag primarily wraps the entire contents of the web page, although not all of those contents are actually displayed directly on the web page. For example, the head tag will actually have some meta information about the page, but it’s not actually rendered in the web browser, the title tag actually belongs to the head tag. And while it’s not rendered on the page, it’s actually going to denote the name of the webpage in things like your tabs. So when you open up a page in a new tab, and you have the name of the webpage, there, that’s where that comes from. The body tag is going to have all the rest of the content of the actual website.</description></item><item><title>Basic HTML Part 2</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/03-basic-html-2/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/03-basic-html-2/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script So we talked briefly about CSS or Cascading Style Sheets before when we introduced html 4.0. But we haven’t actually added anything to our webpage yet. So far, our webpage is completely static and unstyled. So Cascading Style Sheets will allow you to modify things like font colors, background colors, styles, as far as like font types, spacing, layouts, pretty much anything that deals with style or looks, the cascading style sheet or the CSS sheet will be able to accommodate that. So how do we actually add any CSS to our web page? Well, we could actually add it directly into the specific tag that we want by adding a style attribute, just like what we did with h ref, but style instead. But this can be very cumbersome, especially as your website grows and becomes very large.</description></item><item><title>The Interactive Web</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/04-interactive-web/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/04-interactive-web/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re gonna be taking a look at interactive web technologies. And now we’ve talked a lot about these things in the past about Web 1.0 vs 2.0. So going from the static plain HTML Web to Web 2.0, where everything is much more dynamic, interactive, more media, more content, more interactive technology. And so we’re going to take a look at how we can actually use some of these to make our websites a little bit more interesting. Some of the primary ones that we’ll be talking about today are the Document Object Model, which is fundamentally how a lot of the Web 2.0 pages actually are structured and work. JavaScript, Ajax, and JSON, which also helped make our webpages a lot more interactive. First, let’s take a look at the Document Object Model or DOM. So the document object model is really how a web page is actually structured. So you can kind of think of the window here as like a tab in your web browser. So the entire contents of that is your window. And in that window, we have history of that web page. So maybe even things like cookies, past searches, past form information, things like that, location information. But then we have the document itself, which is the actual page that we’ve loaded. So your document or HTML, everything that was between the open and close HTML tags, actually goes here.</description></item><item><title>Starting Tic Tac Toe</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/05-tictactoe-page/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/05-tictactoe-page/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at how we might make our Tic Tac Toe game using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. To start out here, we’re going to make a new HTML page. Now this can go straight back into your index.html that we made in the previous videos. The one I’m going to make for this video is going to be called tictactoe.html. And I’m going to save this as all types. As I mentioned, we can just use the files that we had already previously created. Or we can make a new one, if you are using a previously made file, the only things that you might need to actually add in here is replacing our body tag, or just replacing the content with the new Tic Tac Toe stuff that we’re going to be talking about this time. So anyway, so what we actually had just have here, and if I just simply run this file, all I have is my Tic Tac Toe title. So a lot of what we have actually in the PowerPoint slides are also most of the HTML code that I’m copying over today. So if you need that reference, go and pull up those slides. And you can copy and paste a lot of this code in, or you can type it out by hand for some extra practice. The next chunk of code that I’m going to put in here is the actual word that we’re going to use for the Tic Tac Toe game. So let me come and tidy some of this up here. And again, if you remember the previous videos that we did on HTML, you don’t actually have to have proper white spacing, a lot of the time with HTML tags. I’m including proper whitespace, and tabs in here, just so our code looks nice and neat and clean, and it’s a lot easier for us to read.</description></item><item><title>Javascript</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/06-javascript/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/06-javascript/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video we’re gonna be looking at JavaScript. But let’s look into some of the history behind it. To start, we’re going to talk about Brendan Eich. Brendan Eich was actually one of the people who co founded the Mozilla project to of course launching the major browser Firefox, but he’s also the creator of JavaScript. Eich had a master’s degree from the University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign, but then he started working at Silicon Graphics, working about seven years or so on an operating systems project, and primarily a lot of networking code. But he then started at Netscape in 1995. And when he joined Netscape, he really intended to put the language called scheme into the web browsers. Now, Netscape, of course is no longer prevalent in today’s internet world, but Netscape was really primarily one of the leading internet companies back in the mid to late 90s. But as Brendan started to work and putting scheme into the web browser, Netscape noted that his project actually resembled the Java syntax, and pushed really quickly after after that point. His project released a little over a week later, to accommodate Netscape Navigator 2. And so he was really pushed really time pressed underneath, and a lot of pressure to get this language actually released. And it actually underwent many different name changes during that time. One point it was called mocha, then LiveScript, and then eventually called JavaScript all in the same month. While it does resemble Java, JavaScript itself is actually an entirely different category of programming language. While Java is very object oriented JavaScript is more of a as as it sounds, right, more of a scripting programming language designed specifically for the web.</description></item><item><title>Tic Tac Toe JS</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/07-tictactoe-js/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/07-tictactoe-js/index.html</guid><description>JQuery Script Tag In some older videos, the JQuery script tag is shown using http in the URL. This should be changed to https in order to work correctly due to some recent browser security updates. Alternatively, you can always find the correct JQuery script tag by visiting https://releases.jquery.com/ and clicking the “uncompressed” link next to the latest version of JQuery.
Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to start making our Tic Tac Toe game a little bit more interesting by enabling us to actually play the game. So a few pieces that we need before we actually start programming with the JavaScript. The first part is our script tag. So we need to actually embed JavaScript into our web page. So to do that, we’re going to add a couple tags, right after our table or our board that we had before. So down here towards the bottom right above your body tag, right underneath the table tag, we’re going to add our script tags. And these script tags are going to be used to import the JavaScript. So just like what we’ve done with our CSS up here, where our link tag is actually importing our CSS, our Cascading Style Sheets into our page. Our script tag is going to work very much the same. So I’m going to go ahead and just paste these in here. And then let’s go ahead and talk about them. So each script tag has a source attribute, where the source attribute is going to be the actual location of the script that you’re actually pulling in. And inside, typically, you won’t see one unless you’re importing JavaScript. Typically won’t see anything in between the opening and closing tag, but you could just leave the source blank, and actually put the JavaScript straight inside of the tag itself.</description></item><item><title>More Web 2.0</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/08-more-interactive-web/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/08-more-interactive-web/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back, everyone. Now let’s continue our discussion on interactive web technologies. So we’ve done a little bit of JavaScript so far to get our Tic Tac Toe game working. But there are a lot of other technologies out there that really make web 2.0 really work. So in concert with JavaScript, we have Ajax Ajax was released in 2005. And it allowed for a synchronous JavaScript. So really what happens with Ajax is once the web page loads, the JavaScript can run on the webpage. But what if you wanted more data from your web server? Well, typically, what would end up happening is that you would have to have the page refreshed in its entirety in order to get that web request fulfilled. But Ajax allows you to send information back and forth to your web server behind the scenes without having to have the whole entire page reload. This isn’t really useful, because we can have the entire page get loaded once, especially if it’s a really large, complicated page. And then your JavaScript can handle sending requests back and forth to your web server to reload certain things. Like for example, new comments that were on the page, a new likes, or even maybe a new reply to a Reddit thread, this drastically decreases the amount of time you spend browsing the web page by having to wait for the entire page to reload, just to see who the latest comment was on your post. Now, in this case, this also applies with XML, which we’ll talk about here in a little bit. Now, most Ajax anymore will actually heavily favor using JSON, which we’ll also talk about here in a little bit. But let’s take a look at XML first. xml stands for the Extensible Markup Language, oh, what really XML is, is kind of looks like HTML.</description></item><item><title>The Machine is Us/ing Us (Final Version)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/09-machine-us/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/09-machine-us/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>CIS Linux</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/10-cs-linux/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/10-cs-linux/index.html</guid><description>VPN Off Campus To access CIS Linux while off campus, you must use K-State’s VPN. You do not need to use the VPN when connected to KSU Wireless or KSU Housing wifi. Here is a reference for the K-State VPN including how to install and how to use it: https://www.k-state.edu/it/cybersecurity/vpn/
Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, I’m going to talk a little bit about how we can get connected to the CS Linux server. So when we’re working with our webpages, we can actually open up our web page just fine in our local web browser if you’re working on your computer. For this class, we’re going to be hosting our web pages on CS Linux, so we can actually access them throughout the web. Because if we’re just working on our local machines, we’re not going to be able to access that website from anywhere else in the world. In order to achieve this, we’re going to need a tool that allows us to use SSH. The easiest way for Windows is to download something like PuTTY, or MobaXterm. If you decide to download or use PuTTY, you’ll be taken to a website once you actually click the download link on their main page to something that looks like this. Now, the file that you’ll actually need, you can kind of ignore all the alternative binary files down here, all you need is the MSI Windows Installer and pick if you’re using a 32 bit machine or 64 bit machine. Most people are going to be using the 64 bit machine. So that’s how you can download PuTTY. If you do a quick Google search for MobaXterm, you’ll actually find the download for that as well. Both of these are 100% free; although, MobaXterm does have a pro version, which essentially allows you to save more connections than the standard version. But for most people, the standard free version will be just fine. If you’re actually a CS major, I encourage you to download and install MobaXterm over PuTTY, because it can actually be a lot more useful and flexible for you in the future for other classes. But PuTTY will work just fine for those as well.</description></item></channel></rss>