<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RSA Encryption :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/10-rsa/index.html</link><description>Error in Video In the video, the values of d and e are swapped at one point. Thankfully, this doesn’t matter since they are commutative and can be used in any order, but it is a bit confusing. We’ll correct this video in the future!
Resources Slides RSA Calculator Worksheet Video Script Let’s take a look at one modern form of encryption called RSA encryption. RSA was developed in 1977, and it was named for the three creators- Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir, and Leonard Adelman. RSA encryption uses the product of two large prime numbers to generate a key that’s used to encrypt data, and the strength of the key really depends on the difficulty of factoring that large number back into its two prime numbers. So for example, if we say our key number is 1071. Can we factor that into the two prime numbers? We could do it eventually, but we’d have to check a lot of different numbers to see what it was. So now imagine that 1071, instead of being a number with just four digits, was a number that had 64 digits in it. That’s really the size of the prime number products that we’re talking about when we do RSA encryption. And so really, the key to RSA encryption is the fact that it’s very, very difficult to factor a large number like that into the two unique prime numbers that are used to create it. So let’s take a look at how RSA encryption works to see why that’s important and why it can create a system that is easily broken if that rule doesn’t hold.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/10-rsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>