<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Searching the Web :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/02-searching-web/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script So in this video, we’re going to reiterate a little bit what we talked about with our relational database, right? Because the whole point of the relational database is that we can store lots of information in a very structured way that is easily searchable. That’s really important in today’s world, because we have the World Wide Web, right, the internet, it’s huge. Now that we know how to store data in a reasonable fashion, we have to talk about where most of the data in the world is actually stored. And for that, really is just the internet. So at the highest level, right, we can think of the internet as a very big, very big, completely unstructured database of all of the information in the world, right, because pretty much almost everything is connected to the internet anymore. Not everything, but pretty much. Some parts of it are very structured, and very well formed and easily searchable. But generally, it will never be as well structured as we’d like. And one structure might be entirely different than another. And so it’s not going to be very uniform across the entire internet. However, we are pretty much constantly using tools like Google to find information and the vast amount of data that is out there on the web, and it does a pretty good job, doesn’t it? When you do a Google search most of the time you find what you’re looking for. So how do we go about finding information in a big giant unstructured pile of data that really is pretty much like finding a needle in a haystack, as far as Internet is concerned. So that task is the job of information retrieval specialist, and the algorithms and research they do. In a base form, right, let’s say we want to find some information on a very simple Internet, maybe this is back in the early early, early days, where there was pretty much nothing out there.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/02-searching-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>