




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conditionals on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conditionals on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:23:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/00-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/00-intro/</guid>
      <description>Working with Boolean values in programming is a very important skill to learn. Previously, we saw how to work with Boolean values in pseudocode, and in this lab we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the same content in the Python programming language. Once again, feel free to refer to other content in this course for information about Booleans, Boolean Logic, Boolean algebra, and other related topics.
In this lab, we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create Boolean values in Python, as well as the various Boolean operators and comparators that can we can use in our code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pseudocode If</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/01-pseudocode-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/01-pseudocode-if/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Now that we understand how to use Boolean values in our pseudocode programs, it&amp;rsquo;s time to put those values to use. One way to think of the result of a Boolean expression is that it helps us make a decision in our programs. For example, if we want to do something special in our program when the user inputs the value $42$ into the variable x, then we can write the Boolean expression x = 42 to help us decide if the user input the correct value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pseudocode If-Else</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/02-pseudocode-if-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/02-pseudocode-if-else/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Another important type of conditional statement is the if-else statement. In an if-else statement, we can run either one piece of code if the Boolean expression evaluates to true, or another piece of code if it evaluates to false. It will always choose one option or the other, based on the value in the Boolean expression.
The general structure of an if-else statement in pseudocode is shown here:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pseudocode Testing</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/03-pseudocode-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/03-pseudocode-testing/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides One important concept to understand when writing if statements and if-else statements is the control flow of the program. Before we learned about conditional statements, our programs had a linear control flow - there was exactly one pathway through the program, no matter what. Each time we ran the program, the same code would be executed each time in the same order. However, with the introduction of conditional statements, this is no longer the case.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python If</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/04-python-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/04-python-if/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Boolean expressions in Python can be used in a variety of ways. One of the most important things we can do with a Boolean expression is affect the control flow of our program using a conditional statement.
Recall that a conditional statement is a type of statement that allows us to choose to run different pieces of code based on the value given in a Boolean expression. The simplest conditional statement is the if statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python If-Else</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/05-python-if-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/05-python-if-else/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Python also supports another kind of conditional statement, the if-else statement. Just like in pseudocode, an if-else statement contains a single Boolean expression, but two blocks of code. If the Boolean expression evaluates to True, then one block of statements is executed. If it is False, then the other block will be executed.
The general structure of an if-else statement in Python is shown below:
if &amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;block of statements 1&amp;gt; else: &amp;lt;block of statements 2&amp;gt; Notice that the else keyword is followed by a colon, just like the first line of the if-else statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Testing</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/06-python-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/06-python-testing/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Previously, we saw how important it was to consider many possible test inputs when testing a program that contains a conditional statement. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through one more example, this time in Python, to get some more practice with creating test inputs for conditional statements.
Example Program For this example, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following program in Python:
def main(): a = int(input(&amp;#34;Enter a number: &amp;#34;)) b = int(input(&amp;#34;Enter a number: &amp;#34;)) if a // b &amp;gt;= 5: # Branch 1 print(&amp;#34;{} goes into {} at least 5 times&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/07-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/7-conditionals/07-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we covered several major important topics. Let&amp;rsquo;s quickly review them.
Pseudocode Conditional Statements if statement IF(&amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;) { &amp;lt;block of statements&amp;gt; } if-else statement IF(&amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;) { &amp;lt;block of statements 1&amp;gt; } ELSE { &amp;lt;block of statements 2&amp;gt; } Python Conditional Statements if statement if &amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;block of statements&amp;gt; if-else statement if &amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;block of statements 1&amp;gt; else: &amp;lt;block of statements 2&amp;gt; Testing Branch Coverage - all possible branches are executed at least once Path Coverage - all possible paths through branches are executed at least once Edge Cases - values that are near the point where Boolean expressions go from false to true </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>