<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Insertion Sort :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/06-algorithms/04-insertion-sort/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script In these next couple of videos, we’re going to introduce the concept of sorting algorithms. Sorting algorithms are used when we want to arrange sets of data in order either from smallest to largest or largest to smallest in our computer programs. As it turns out, there are many different ways that we can sort our data using different algorithms. And each of those algorithms have unique characteristics that make them suitable for certain types of data in certain situations. To really explore sorting algorithms, we’re going to perform these sorting algorithms using a deck of cards. So if you have access to a deck of cards, I encourage you to go find one and take out maybe 8 or 10 cards in a certain order. I have the cards Ace through 10 here, and you’ll be able to follow along with our examples on these next few videos. Before we get started, I’d like you to take the cards that you have selected, shuffled them up a little bit, and then lay them out in front of you and try and sort them in order from smallest to largest. And while you do that, I’d like you to think in your mind about the exact steps that you’re following. For example, are you looking for the smallest card and moving it to one side, or looking for the largest card and moving it to the other side? Or are you trying to arrange little bits of it at a time and slowly put those pieces together until they form the full sort of deck of cards, it might be really interesting to see how the method that you naturally follow matches up with one of these algorithms that we’re going to take a look at. In particular, we’re going to look at four different sorting algorithms, insertion Sort, bubble sort, merge, sort, and quicksort.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/06-algorithms/04-insertion-sort/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>