




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python Loops on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python Loops on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:23:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>While Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/01-while-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/01-while-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides The first type of loop to explore in Python is the while loop. A while loop uses a Boolean expression, and will repeat the code inside of the loop as long as the Boolean expression evaluates to True. These loops are typically used when we want to repeat some steps, but we aren&amp;rsquo;t sure exactly how many times it must be done. Instead, we typically know that there is some condition that must be True while we repeat the code, and once it turns False we can stop looping and continue with the program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/02-for-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/02-for-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Python also includes a second type of loop that is very useful, the for loop. Just like in pseudocode, a for loop is used when we want to repeat the steps a certain number of times. However, in Python, we can&amp;rsquo;t just say that we want to repeat something $10$ times. Instead, we use the built-in range() function in Python to generate a list of numbers that we use in our loop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input with Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/03-input-with-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/03-input-with-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Loops in Python are also a great way to handle situations where a user must input a value that meets certain criteria. Previously, we used an if statement to determine if the input was valid, but if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t valid all we could do was print an error and end the program. If we use a loop instead, we can prompt the user to provide additional input until we receive a valid value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/04-testing-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/04-testing-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Another important aspect of working with loops in code is learning how to properly test programs that contain loops. So, let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the methods we can use when testing our programs containing loops to make sure they work correctly and won&amp;rsquo;t run into any problems.
Branch and Path Coverage Loops, like conditional statements, introduce different branches and paths into our programs. So, one of the first steps when testing these programs is to develop a set of inputs that will execute each branch of the code, as well as finding inputs that will execute multiple different paths through the program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worked Example</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/05-worked-example/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/05-worked-example/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve learned all about using loops in Python, let&amp;rsquo;s go through a complete worked example to see how all the pieces fit together. As we continue to develop larger and more complex programs, it is helpful to observe the entire process from start to finish so we can see how to easily develop a program one step at a time. Once we&amp;rsquo;ve created our program, we&amp;rsquo;ll also perform a bit of testing to make sure that it works correctly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/06-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/11-python-loops/06-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we introduced several major important topics in Python. Let&amp;rsquo;s quickly review them.
Python While Loops While loops in Python will execute while a Boolean expression evaluates to true.
while &amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;block of statements&amp;gt;Range Function The range() function in Python is used to generate a list of numbers. It can be used in three ways:
range(stop) - numbers from $0$ up to (but not including) stop range(start, stop) - numbers from start up to (but not including) stop range(start, stop, step) - numbers from start up to (but not including) stop, with step between each number.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>