<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/02-big-data/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re going to be taking a look at big data. So exactly how big is big data? So here’s a slide of the metric prefixes. And so which ones do you think constitute as big data? or big data? Today, we’re talking about data anywhere from gigabytes to petabytes and beyond. And the future, we may even be dealing with exabytes of data. I said, gigabytes, right. But I can have a single video or even in these lecture series, that might be a gigabytes worth of data. And in the grand scheme of things, right, that’s just one video. But if you break down that gigabyte worth of data, you can actually start to chunk that up into lots of different lots of different parts, right? If we’re recording in 4k, for example, as a significant number of frames per second in the video, along with a significant number of pixels. And if you tack on the sound information with that as well. It is a significant amount of information that can be packed into a single gigabyte, big data is going to deal with or one, how do we actually store all of this information? How do we use this information? And how do we get information out of it, right, because we can have lots of information. But without any algorithms or way or ways of actually presenting that information becomes pretty much useless at the end of the day.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/02-big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>