




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Course Introduction - Spring 2022</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/01-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/01-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Previous Versions Video Script [Slide 1]
Hello and welcome to the Computational Core program!
My name is Emily Alfs-Votipka, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be one of the instructors for this program. My contact information is shown here, and is also listed on the syllabus.
[Slide 2]
There are many other instructors and TAs for this program that you may interact with or see in the tutorial videos. They all have been instrumental in the development of this program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Canvas &amp; Codio</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/02-navigating-canvas-codio/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/02-navigating-canvas-codio/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Codio Documentation Video Script This course makes extensive use of several features of Canvas which you may or may not have worked with before. To give you the best experience in this course, this video will briefly describe those features and the best way to access them.
When you first access the course on Canvas, you will be shown this homepage. It contains quick links to the course syllabus and Piazza discussion boards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where to Find Help</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/03-where-to-find-help/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/03-where-to-find-help/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides K-State IT Help Desk - Email helpdesk@ksu.edu K-State Online Canvas Help Instructure Canvas Guides Codio Documentation Codio Support K-State Libraries K-State CS Support K-State CS Advising K-State Engineering Student Services K-State Office of Student Life K-State Report It Video Script [Slide 1]
As you work on the materials in this course, you may run into questions or problems and need assistance. This video reviews the various types of help available to you in this course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You&#39;ll Learn</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/04-what-youll-learn/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/04-what-youll-learn/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Code.org Quotes Video Script Finally, before embarking on this program, let&amp;rsquo;s take a brief minute to review what you&amp;rsquo;ll learn by the time you complete the program.
Of course, the biggest and most impactful outcome will be learning how to write computer programs. Throughout the Computational Core program, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn either the Java or Python programming language, and get to a point where you are quite proficient with your language of choice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn Programming</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/05-how-to-learn-programming/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/05-how-to-learn-programming/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides The Science of Learning Programming from Nathan Bean&amp;rsquo;s CIS 400 Textbook The Power of Believing You Can Improve | Carol Dweck - TED Talk on Mindsets and the Power of &amp;ldquo;Yet&amp;rdquo; The New Science of Learning: How to Learn in Haromony with your Brain by Terry Doyle and Todd Zakrajsek - Great Book on Learning Constructivism on Wikipedia - Article about Jean Piaget&amp;rsquo;s Learning Philosophy Toward a Developmental Epistemology of Computer Programming by Raymond Lister - Introduces the Stages of Learning to Program Video Script Before we launch into the course itself, I wanted to take a few minutes to share some information with you regarding what we know about how students learn to program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CC 110 Syllabus - Fall 2023</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/index.html</guid>
      <description>CC 110 - Introduction to Computing - Spring 2023 Previous Versions Instructor Contact Information Instructor: Safia Malallah (safia AT ksu DOT edu)
I use she/her pronouns. Feel free to share your own pronouns with me, and I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to use them! Office: DUE 2161 Office Hours: safiamalallah.com/calendar Want to meet with me outside of my regular office hours? https://calendly.com/safiamalallah Preferred Methods of Communication: Email: Please use &amp;ldquo;cc110-help&amp;rdquo; (cc110-help@ksuemailprod.onmicrosoft.com if not on web-mail) for all communication regarding these courses as it allows instructors and TAs to provide a clear and detailed response, as well as easily store and record communication for reference later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plagiarism Policy</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/07-plagiarism/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/00-introduction/07-plagiarism/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources K-State Honor &amp;amp; Integrity System Video Script &amp;ldquo;On my honor, as a student, I have neither given nor received unauthorized aid on this academic work.&amp;rdquo; - K-State Honor Pledge
Plagiarism is a very serious concern in this course, and something that we do not take lightly. Computer programs and code are especially easy targets for plagiarism due to how easy it is to copy and manipulate code in such a way that it is unrecognizable as the original source but still performs correctly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>