<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction to HTML :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/01-introduction/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the Hypertext Markup Language. This is a continuation of our previous videos where we talked about the history of the internet, as well as how the internet actually worked. Now, in those videos, we took a look at Sir Tim Berners-Lee, who invented the Hypertext Markup Language along with the web server and the technology that was used to actually serve those web pages. The first version of HTML that Sir Tim Berners-Lee released in 1990, was still a huge improvement over the content that was being served on the Internet at that time. We really had no unify language that we were able to use to distribute information on the web. HTML 1.0 brought that to light. Even though throughout the 90s, HTML was a pretty static language, meaning that our webpages were still pretty straightforward, there really wasn’t a whole lot of dynamic content. It wasn’t until Web 4.0 released and the late 90s and even into the early 2000s, where we started to make the transition to the Web 2.0 era, where we started to see a lot more social media type content, and very dynamic content being hosted on the web, like a lot of media as well. The big landmark version of HTML, HTML 4.0, was really important because this is also where Cascading Style Sheets came into play. Before, we could still style our web pages to a certain extent, but all of those styles were actually built into the page.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/01-introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>