<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Starting Tic Tac Toe :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/05-tictactoe-page/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at how we might make our Tic Tac Toe game using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. To start out here, we’re going to make a new HTML page. Now this can go straight back into your index.html that we made in the previous videos. The one I’m going to make for this video is going to be called tictactoe.html. And I’m going to save this as all types. As I mentioned, we can just use the files that we had already previously created. Or we can make a new one, if you are using a previously made file, the only things that you might need to actually add in here is replacing our body tag, or just replacing the content with the new Tic Tac Toe stuff that we’re going to be talking about this time. So anyway, so what we actually had just have here, and if I just simply run this file, all I have is my Tic Tac Toe title. So a lot of what we have actually in the PowerPoint slides are also most of the HTML code that I’m copying over today. So if you need that reference, go and pull up those slides. And you can copy and paste a lot of this code in, or you can type it out by hand for some extra practice. The next chunk of code that I’m going to put in here is the actual word that we’re going to use for the Tic Tac Toe game. So let me come and tidy some of this up here. And again, if you remember the previous videos that we did on HTML, you don’t actually have to have proper white spacing, a lot of the time with HTML tags. I’m including proper whitespace, and tabs in here, just so our code looks nice and neat and clean, and it’s a lot easier for us to read.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/05-tictactoe-page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>