<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>More Web 2.0 :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/08-more-interactive-web/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back, everyone. Now let’s continue our discussion on interactive web technologies. So we’ve done a little bit of JavaScript so far to get our Tic Tac Toe game working. But there are a lot of other technologies out there that really make web 2.0 really work. So in concert with JavaScript, we have Ajax Ajax was released in 2005. And it allowed for a synchronous JavaScript. So really what happens with Ajax is once the web page loads, the JavaScript can run on the webpage. But what if you wanted more data from your web server? Well, typically, what would end up happening is that you would have to have the page refreshed in its entirety in order to get that web request fulfilled. But Ajax allows you to send information back and forth to your web server behind the scenes without having to have the whole entire page reload. This isn’t really useful, because we can have the entire page get loaded once, especially if it’s a really large, complicated page. And then your JavaScript can handle sending requests back and forth to your web server to reload certain things. Like for example, new comments that were on the page, a new likes, or even maybe a new reply to a Reddit thread, this drastically decreases the amount of time you spend browsing the web page by having to wait for the entire page to reload, just to see who the latest comment was on your post. Now, in this case, this also applies with XML, which we’ll talk about here in a little bit. Now, most Ajax anymore will actually heavily favor using JSON, which we’ll also talk about here in a little bit. But let’s take a look at XML first. xml stands for the Extensible Markup Language, oh, what really XML is, is kind of looks like HTML.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/08-more-interactive-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>