<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Universal Computers :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:02:14 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/01-introduction/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/01-introduction/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back, everyone. In today’s video, we’re going to be talking about universal computers. Now to pretty much pick up where we left off a while ago when we were talking about Boolean logic, Claude Shannon had just proposed a way to take electrical circuits and represent any Boolean logical statement with them. And so this was a huge turning point in the history of computer science. But how did we make the leap from Boolean logic on electrical circuits to the modern computers that we have today, and we’ll talk a little bit about that gap here today, but there will still be some missing parts that we’ll talk about later. But this brings us to Herman Hollerith, who at the time was a United States Census office employee, and he was tasked with coming up with a better way to calculate the census result. Because at the time, calculating the US census was incredibly slow. The 1880 census alone took eight years to tabulate, which really kind of defeats the purpose of a census, right? If you only know how many people you have in your country, eight years after the fact, the census was actually taken.</description></item><item><title>Top Secret Rosies</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/02-top-secret-rosies/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/02-top-secret-rosies/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Top Secret Rosies Website</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/03-top-secret-rosies-web/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/03-top-secret-rosies-web/index.html</guid><description>Top Secret Rosies Website</description></item><item><title>Electronic Computing (Crash Course)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/04-electronic-computing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/04-electronic-computing/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Imitation Game</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/05-the-imitation-game/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/05-the-imitation-game/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>What ARE Universal Computers?</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/06-what-are-universal-computers/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/06-what-are-universal-computers/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script So what really is a universal computer? We’ve thrown that term around a little bit. We’ve also talked about what it means to be a truly general purpose computer or reprogrammable computer compared to a fixed program computer like what the original Difference Engine was. So, this is what made the ENIAC so unique as well as the mark one, although to a lesser extent. is the fact that they are considered the world’s first true universal computers. So what do you think it means to be called a universal computer? Well, a universal computer can simulate any real world computer given infinite time and infinite memory. So if you imagine taking your cell phone or even something as small as like the little Raspberry Pi or a smartwatch. And if it was truly a universal computer, if you gave it enough time and enough memory, it could pretty much do anything any other computer could do. So compare that to some supercomputer right like Beocat that we have in the computer science department here at K-State. Right, a universal computer can do anything that Beocat can do, given enough time and give it given enough space.</description></item><item><title>Alan Turing</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/07-alan-turing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/07-alan-turing/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modern Turing Machines</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/08-modern-turing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/08-modern-turing/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Turing Machine Example</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/09-turing-machine-example/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/09-turing-machine-example/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Hello everyone in this video we’re going to take a look at a detailed example on how a Turing machine may actually perform a common operation that we would do with a regular program. Remember that our Turing machine has eight simple instructions that it can execute using the control arm or the the reader that the machine or the program is actually loaded on. But it can simply move left or right one, it can write ones and zeros and it can also read and also jump around in the program as well. So these eight simple steps remember represent a truly universal computer given enough time, and given enough memory, it can perform any operation any other real world computer could actually do. So here’s an example of a basic program on our Turing machine. So our reader or the Turing machine itself would be preloaded with this program. In this situation, we’re going to assume that we start with two elements or two items or two pieces of data on our tape. And these items, remember, all we’re dealing with here are ones and zeros, nothing else.</description></item><item><title>Von Neumann Architecture</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/10-von-neumann/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/10-von-neumann/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Unfortunately, with all the computers that we’ve talked about so far, they don’t really look like the computers that we have today, right? These machines took up entire, literally entire rooms and weighed tons and had millions upon millions of different individual parts. And so how did we get from a giant computer that takes up our room to a computer that fits on your wrist? And so the last piece of that puzzle comes to us from John Von Neumann, and some call him the last of the great mathematicians. And his accomplishments are truly outstanding, although you may hear some feedback against calling him the last of the great mathematician. But where does Von Neumann actually come into play with computer science history?</description></item><item><title>Pattern on the Stone Reading</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/11-pots-reading/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/05-universal-computers/11-pots-reading/index.html</guid><description>Read Pattern on the Stone, Chapter 4.</description></item></channel></rss>