




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math Operators on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math Operators on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:23:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Numeric Data</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/01-numeric-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/01-numeric-data/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Previously, we learned about strings and string values in pseudocode. Recall that a string is just text inside of a set of quotation marks &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, such as &amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Willie Wildcat&amp;quot;. In technical terms, a string is an example of a data type in programming. A data type defines the way a particular value can be stored in a computer. For text values, we use the string data type.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pseudocode Operators</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/02-pseudocode-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/02-pseudocode-operators/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides Now that we have the ability to store numerical data in variables in pseudocode, we should also learn how to manipulate that data into something new. To do that, let&amp;rsquo;s learn about operators. An operator in programming is a special symbol that can be used in an expression to manipulate the data in some way. Most operators are binary operators, which means they perform an operation that uses two values as input and produces a single value as output.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integers &amp; Floats</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/03-integers-floats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/03-integers-floats/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve only worked with string values in Python. Strings are a very useful data type in programming languages such as Python, but they are very limited in their use. Recall that a data type simply defines how a particular value is stored in a computer. The str data type is used to store string values in Python.
Python supports many different data types for handling various data that we&amp;rsquo;d like to store and manipulate in our programs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Operators</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/04-python-operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/04-python-operators/</guid>
      <description>Resources Slides We can also use Python to perform mathematical operations on numerical data using operators. So, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly review the operators we&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far, and introduce a couple of new operators that are unique to Python.
Mathematical Operators Python supports the same mathematical operators that we&amp;rsquo;ve already seen in pseudocode. The only exception is the the modulo operation is performed using the percent symbol % instead of the MOD keyword.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/05-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/4-math-operators/05-summary/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we covered several major important topics. Let&amp;rsquo;s quickly review them.
Data Types in Pseudocode string data type stores text. Use STRING(expression) to convert an expression to a string if possible. number data type stores numbers. Use NUMBER(expression) to convert an expression to a number if possible. Math Operators in Pseudocode + Addition - Subtraction * Multiplication / Division MOD Modulo (the remainder of division) Pseudocode Order of Operations Parentheses Multiplication, Division and Modulo from left to right Addition and Subtraction from left to right Data Types in Python str data type stores text (strings).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>