<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Storing Passwords :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/02-storing-passwords/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script So finally, let’s talk about storing passwords securely in your applications. And there are a lot of different ways you can store passwords so that users could use them to authenticate. Let’s take a look at that. First, obviously, we could store the password itself. The user types in a password, we store that password in the database. Great, right? They type that password in again, we check it to make sure they typed in the same password. If they did, they let them in. That sounds like a really great system, doesn’t it? Hopefully, you’re cringing a little bit thinking about this. Because obviously, websites that have databases on them get hacked all the time. And if a hacker gets access to this database, they have your password. Simple as that. There’s nothing that they have to do, there’s no decryption they have to worry about, they get your password. And of course, one of the weaknesses of people on the internet is we tend to use the same password over and over again. Raise your hand, if you do that. I do. I use the same password a lot of places on the internet, it’s something I probably shouldn’t do. But I do. And so if somebody gets one of my passwords, they might be able to use that password to log into other websites that I use that same password on. So this is obviously not very secure. And the only thing that they need to compromise this is database access. As soon as they access the database, they have all the passwords, and it’s really simple so we probably shouldn’t do this.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/02-storing-passwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>