<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Big Data :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/index.html</link><description>Image Source: theconversation.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:20:44 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hans Rosling's 200 Countries, 200 Years, 4 Minutes - The Joy of Stats - BBC Four</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/01-200-years/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/01-200-years/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/02-big-data/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/02-big-data/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re going to be taking a look at big data. So exactly how big is big data? So here’s a slide of the metric prefixes. And so which ones do you think constitute as big data? or big data? Today, we’re talking about data anywhere from gigabytes to petabytes and beyond. And the future, we may even be dealing with exabytes of data. I said, gigabytes, right. But I can have a single video or even in these lecture series, that might be a gigabytes worth of data. And in the grand scheme of things, right, that’s just one video. But if you break down that gigabyte worth of data, you can actually start to chunk that up into lots of different lots of different parts, right? If we’re recording in 4k, for example, as a significant number of frames per second in the video, along with a significant number of pixels. And if you tack on the sound information with that as well. It is a significant amount of information that can be packed into a single gigabyte, big data is going to deal with or one, how do we actually store all of this information? How do we use this information? And how do we get information out of it, right, because we can have lots of information. But without any algorithms or way or ways of actually presenting that information becomes pretty much useless at the end of the day.</description></item><item><title>HealthMap.org</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/03-health-map/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/03-health-map/index.html</guid><description>HealthMap</description></item><item><title>Google Trends</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/04-google-trends/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/04-google-trends/index.html</guid><description>Google Trends</description></item><item><title>The Four V's</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/05-four-vs/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/05-four-vs/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script To really understand how big data can be useful, we can look at four different aspects that are usually referred to as the four V’s of big data. These are volume. So how much data there is a variety, how much or how little variety actually exist, velocity, just how fast data is being produced and or received. And veracity. How accurate is that data, there’s also a fifth fee, typically referred to as value. But we won’t actually include that in this particular lecture. But if you are looking at Big Data information online, you might see that fifth V out there called value. But let’s take a deeper dive into each one of these.</description></item><item><title>Map Reduce</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/06-map-reduce/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/20-big-data/06-map-reduce/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script One of the last things I want to talk about here with big data is some of the algorithms that we can actually use to work with this sheer amount of information. So one that I want to highlight here is called MapReduce. Oh, MapReduce is a very well known algorithm and big data realm. And now it’s been, of course, transformed significantly, since its original inception, inception, to handle even larger amounts of information. But the idea here is that we take a very large amount of information, let’s say text, and then we map it to smaller parts, break it out, and then we recombine that and to produce a final result. Okay. And so if you can use this as an example, right, if we’re trying to, let’s say, sort of deck of cards, okay, if I asked if I give you a whole bunch, or if I give you a full deck of cards that is completely shuffled, but I want you to sort it out in numerical order, as well as the suits would actually take you a little bit of time to actually achieve that task. But if I were allow it, if I gave you a deck of cards in a group, well, so let’s say I gave a group of 10 people, one single deck of cards, and I said, sort do the same thing, it will take them significantly less time than it will if I gave just one person a deck of cards to actually achieve that end result.</description></item></channel></rss>