<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/01-intro/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script In this module, we’re going to take a look at one of the most important applications of computer science and modern technology- the field of cryptography. Cryptography is the study of ways to communicate securely and privately in the presence of third parties. If you think about it, cryptography is very important today with the rise of the Internet and modern technology. Any data that’s transmitted over the internet can be intercepted by just about anyone from your internet service provider all the way to the website that you’re communicating with, and anybody in between. Remember, the internet is built upon open standards, and so anybody can understand the packet formats and deconstruct them very quickly. So we need a way that we can encrypt and secure the data inside of those packets. So they can only be opened by the intended recipients, and that’s where the field of cryptography comes in. There were lots of historical Computer Science professionals interested in cryptography. Charles Babbage was very fascinated by it. Alan Turing was especially involved in cryptography, and Claude Shannon, were all involved in the field of cryptography. Also, surprisingly, the author Edgar Allan Poe was one of the people that was really excited about cryptography outside of computer scientists, and in fact, helped popularize cryptography as a word game that you might see in your newspaper.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/01-intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>