<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:02:51 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Passwords</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/01-passwords/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/01-passwords/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script In this module, we’re going to discuss a lot of topics related to cyber security. Cyber Security is another important research area in computer science, and it’s one that directly impacts a lot of computer users in their daily lives. So in cybersecurity, we really are asking ourselves one big question, how do we keep our data secure, and that’s really all it comes down to. We’re trying to secure data both on our computers, but also as we transmitted across the Internet, and any other communication technologies we might be using. And so we’re going to talk about some different ways that we can keep our data secure on our computers.</description></item><item><title>Storing Passwords</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/02-storing-passwords/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/02-storing-passwords/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script So finally, let’s talk about storing passwords securely in your applications. And there are a lot of different ways you can store passwords so that users could use them to authenticate. Let’s take a look at that. First, obviously, we could store the password itself. The user types in a password, we store that password in the database. Great, right? They type that password in again, we check it to make sure they typed in the same password. If they did, they let them in. That sounds like a really great system, doesn’t it? Hopefully, you’re cringing a little bit thinking about this. Because obviously, websites that have databases on them get hacked all the time. And if a hacker gets access to this database, they have your password. Simple as that. There’s nothing that they have to do, there’s no decryption they have to worry about, they get your password. And of course, one of the weaknesses of people on the internet is we tend to use the same password over and over again. Raise your hand, if you do that. I do. I use the same password a lot of places on the internet, it’s something I probably shouldn’t do. But I do. And so if somebody gets one of my passwords, they might be able to use that password to log into other websites that I use that same password on. So this is obviously not very secure. And the only thing that they need to compromise this is database access. As soon as they access the database, they have all the passwords, and it’s really simple so we probably shouldn’t do this.</description></item><item><title>Social Engineering</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/03-social-engineering/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/03-social-engineering/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Another area of cybersecurity that we should discuss is social engineering. Social engineering is all about using techniques to compromise the system by exploiting the users directly instead of the system security itself. And this is a really important concept. There’s an old saying, in computer science that a system is only as secure as the users that use that system. It’s kind of a play off the idea of a system is only as secure as its weakest link. And in most cases, the weakest link is the user itself. And so on the next few slides, we’re going to take a look at some different ways that you can use social engineering, to maybe break into a computer system and what those things look like so that we can defend against those. So a great example of social engineering is trying to get some information from somebody that they don’t want to give. And a great example of that would be a bank account number. So if I wanted to get someone’s bank account number, how do you think I could go about that using social engineering? Take a minute to think about it. So while this example may not work that well in today’s world, because not many people carry around checkbooks. If you have a checkbook, look at your checkbook at the bottom of your checks, and see what’s printed there. Hopefully, you should realize that printed at the bottom of your checks are two numbers. One of them is the routing number that identifies your bank, and the other number is your bank account number. And so I think one of the best ways to do this was actually discovered by Gru in the movie Despicable Me selling cookies. He had his girls sell Girl Scout cookies, and as long as he said, “Oh, I can only accept checks.” A lot of people might not think twice about writing a check for a Girl Scout troop, but that check includes your bank account information. And so with a little bit more work, you could probably use that information very nefariously against the people that wrote those checks. So even though it’s something that we don’t really think about giving out very often, it’s right there out in the open if we know how to get it.</description></item><item><title>DEFCON Social Engineering CTF Report</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/04-defcon/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/17-cybersecurity/04-defcon/index.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>