<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bits and Boolean Algebra :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:02:51 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/01-introduction/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/01-introduction/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Introduction (Slide 1-2) For this lesson, we’re going to be talking primarily about Boolean logic, Boolean algebra and how that plays into computer science and the foundations of how important that is and the role it plays and what we do. So before we get started, and before we can talk about things such as Boolean logic, we need to know where it came from. That leads us to Aristotle, way back in the 300 BC, as you may know, right Aristotle is one of the fathers of modern philosophy and logic among many other things. He studied under Plato, who himself was taught by Socrates and was also the teacher of Alexander the Great, so pretty much affected the entire world of Western philosophy that came after him. One of his major contributions was this idea of using formal logic to prove a point, then this form of logic, also known as Aristotelian logic, a point is proven based off of a series of premises.</description></item><item><title>Operators</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/02-operators/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/02-operators/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Boolean Operators (Slide 6) And Let’s take a look at what the Boolean and operator does out in this Venn diagram here we’re going to kind of use these to showcase where the Boolean statements that we’re checking out with the Boolean operator where these statements are actually evaluated to be true. So if we assume that we are two facts here, A and B are both true. So let’s say this inner circle here, this left circle here represents a and this right circle here represents B and the square on the outside represents everything else. So when a and b are not, so if A and B are both true, then the statement evaluates to true. So the left hand side and the right hand side of the operator both must be true in order for the whole statement to be true. If A is false, or B is true. false, then the whole thing would be false. Now if we introduce a third fact, see, we kind of get the same results, right. So similar kind of story with the Venn diagram. Here we have a, b, and c. But notice that this little square here where we were actually filled in over here is no longer filled in. And that’s because all three facts must be true for the whole statement to evaluate to true. So a has to be true, B has to be true. And C has to be true in order for the whole statement to evaluate true.</description></item><item><title>Boolean Algebra</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/03-algebra/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/03-algebra/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script DeMorgan’s Theorem (Slide 7) So with all these new tools, we needed some new algebraic rules to really deal with them. Thankfully, most of the rules you know, apply quite well, but there’s one rule that needed to be added. In mathematics. When you multiply by negative one, you have to change the signs. Similarly, Augustus DeMorgan came up with a way to deal with the negation of entire Boolean logic statements. So this becomes very similar to how you multiply a statement or a regular mathematical statement by a negative one. I guess system marking came up with a way to deal with the negation of entire Boolean logic statements. The DeMorgan’s theorem essentially states to treat the NOT operator like the negative sign so you’re going to apply the negative to each of the premises or facts and then swap the operators or basically and become or’s and or’s become hands. So let’s take a look at an example. So if we invert our particular statement here where we have a and b, right, so A and B, not a and b becomes not a or not B, so we negated or applied the knot to a and the knots to b and the knot and becomes or similar idea for or not a or b becomes not a, and not B.</description></item><item><title>Logic to Switches</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/04-logic-to-switches/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/04-logic-to-switches/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Logic via Electrical Switches? (Slide 9) With the new tools from Boole and DeMorgan, others began to see where they could be applied in the real world. In 1886, Charles Sanders Peirce noted in a letter that logical operations could be easily simulated by electrical switches. Many others worked on the idea too many to name here, but 51 years later.</description></item><item><title>Truth Tables</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/05-truth-tables/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/05-truth-tables/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Overview Let’s go through an example of some Boolean logic now that we’ve covered some of the operators and some of the rules that govern the Boolean algebra behind it. A lot of times what you’ll see in computer science, especially when you’re dealing with Boolean logic and complex algorithms, our truth tables, truth tables showcase all the different options for each Boolean variable inside of a Boolean logic statement, as well as what output those particular facts for those variables actually produce. So let’s take a look at an example that we’ve already kind of done with end. So we’ve already explored the statement A and B, and C. You’ve already seen what the Venn diagram for that looks like, but we can also explore what that looks like again here in just a second, but let’s take a look at all possible values that we could actually input for A, B, and C. And if you remember, we’re only going to have two values binary values, either one, or zero or true or false. Now, both work synonymously. And you’ll find both in truth tables. And in fact, what the examples that you’ll be working with, we actually do use ones and zeros for true and false. So if you remember one means true, zero means false. But let’s take a look at how we can actually fill out our truth table here with those particular values. Now, I’m going to go ahead and use T for true and false. But as you could imagine, you could substitute one for true and zero for false and everything would be identical.</description></item><item><title>Boolean Logic (Crash Course)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/06-crash-course/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/06-crash-course/index.html</guid><description>Notes About This Selection In this video, Carrie Anne shares the principals of binary numbers and how we use Boolean Algebra to work with binary values. We get to see the truth tables for the basic statements (or, and, not, xor) as well as their respective logic gates. We also get a good primer for working on more complex statements.</description></item><item><title>Worked Example</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/07-worked-example/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/07-worked-example/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Example 1 (Slide 13) So let’s take a look at example one. And the best way to start this is where the output is actually true. So if we examine this line here, this line and this line, we can see that when B and C are true, output is True. When a and c are true, the output is True, or when all three are true, the output is also true. So a really good way to start is just by coloring in these three facts.</description></item><item><title>Deeper Dive</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/07-deeper-dive/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/07-deeper-dive/index.html</guid><description>Let’s do a bit of a deeper dive into that worked example to explain some of the nuances working with Boolean Logic Expressions, Truth Tables, Venn Diagrams, and the connections between those three. Unfortunately, this is not well explained or covered elsewhere in online resources, but we find that it is really helpful to revisit these concepts here before the end of this module.
Don’t sweat it! This is a lot of conceptual information to digest at once. However, we don’t expect you to become proficient in this right away! This is just meant to be an introduction to the concept of Boolean Logic and Boolean Algebra, which you’ll become more comfortable with over time as you practice your programming skills and take later classes in Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>Pattern on the Stone Reading</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/08-pots-reading/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:53:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/i-concepts/03-bits-and-boolean-algebra/08-pots-reading/index.html</guid><description>Read Pattern on the Stone, Chapter 2.
“The Pattern on the Stone: The Simple Ideas that Make Computers Work” by W. Daniel Hillis. ISBN 046502596X, newer version is also available and will work fine</description></item></channel></rss>