




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pseudocode Loops on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pseudocode Loops on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:23:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>While Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/01-while-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/01-while-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides The first type of loop we&amp;rsquo;ll explore in pseudocode is the while loop. A while loop is an iteration statement that will constantly repeat the code inside of it while a Boolean expression evaluates to true. This is very similar to how an if statement is constructed - we know that the code inside an if statement is only executed if the associated Boolean expression is true.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/02-for-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/02-for-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Another type of loop that is commonly used in programming is the for loop. Instead of a while loop, which only uses a Boolean expression to determine if a loop repeats, a for loop is typically used to iterate a defined number of times, either by counting up or by iterating across a data structure such as a list. We&amp;rsquo;ll learn more about how to use for loops with lists later in this course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input with Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/03-input-with-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/03-input-with-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides One of the most powerful features of loops is to deal with invalid user input. For example, if we want a user to input a positive number, but they accidentally input a negative number instead, what should our program do? Previously, all we could do was print an error and ask the user to run the program again, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t very user friendly or efficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Loops</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/04-testing-loops/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/04-testing-loops/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen many examples of how to use loops in our code, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly discuss some techniques for testing programs that contain loops. Many of these techniques are similar to ones we&amp;rsquo;ve explored when testing conditional statements, but there are a few important nuances to think about.
Branch and Path Coverage First, just like we explored with conditional statements, it is important to test our programs in a way that we execute every possible branch, and try to find every possible path through the program as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worked Example</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/05-worked-example/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/05-worked-example/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Let&amp;rsquo;s go through a complete worked example program so we can see how to use loops to transform a problem statement into a working program. Once we&amp;rsquo;re done, we&amp;rsquo;ll also talk about how we can test the program to determine if it works correctly and won&amp;rsquo;t run into an error.
Problem Statement For this example, we&amp;rsquo;re going to write a simple program to play a variant of the game Nim known as the 21 Game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/06-summary/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/x-cis115-labs/10-pseudocode-loops/06-summary/index.html</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we introduced several major important topics in pseudocode. Let&amp;rsquo;s quickly review them.
Pseudocode While Loops While loops in pseudocode will execute while a Boolean expression evaluates to true.
REPEAT WHILE(&amp;lt;boolean expression&amp;gt;) { &amp;lt;block of statements&amp;gt; }Pseudocode For Loops For loops in pseudocode will execute a set number of times.
REPEAT &amp;lt;n&amp;gt; TIMES { &amp;lt;block of statements&amp;gt; }Input with Loops Loops can be used to request new input from the user if invalid input is received.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>