<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CIS Linux :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/10-cs-linux/index.html</link><description>VPN Off Campus To access CIS Linux while off campus, you must use K-State’s VPN. You do not need to use the VPN when connected to KSU Wireless or KSU Housing wifi. Here is a reference for the K-State VPN including how to install and how to use it: https://www.k-state.edu/it/cybersecurity/vpn/
Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, I’m going to talk a little bit about how we can get connected to the CS Linux server. So when we’re working with our webpages, we can actually open up our web page just fine in our local web browser if you’re working on your computer. For this class, we’re going to be hosting our web pages on CS Linux, so we can actually access them throughout the web. Because if we’re just working on our local machines, we’re not going to be able to access that website from anywhere else in the world. In order to achieve this, we’re going to need a tool that allows us to use SSH. The easiest way for Windows is to download something like PuTTY, or MobaXterm. If you decide to download or use PuTTY, you’ll be taken to a website once you actually click the download link on their main page to something that looks like this. Now, the file that you’ll actually need, you can kind of ignore all the alternative binary files down here, all you need is the MSI Windows Installer and pick if you’re using a 32 bit machine or 64 bit machine. Most people are going to be using the 64 bit machine. So that’s how you can download PuTTY. If you do a quick Google search for MobaXterm, you’ll actually find the download for that as well. Both of these are 100% free; although, MobaXterm does have a pro version, which essentially allows you to save more connections than the standard version. But for most people, the standard free version will be just fine. If you’re actually a CS major, I encourage you to download and install MobaXterm over PuTTY, because it can actually be a lot more useful and flexible for you in the future for other classes. But PuTTY will work just fine for those as well.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/10-cs-linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>