




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Early Computing Machines on Intro CS Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Early Computing Machines on Intro CS Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:23:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Antikythera Mechanism - 2D</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/01-the-antikythera-mech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/01-the-antikythera-mech/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Notes About This Selection This video outlines how the Antikythera Mechanism was found and some of the research that has been done on the mechanism. Getting its name from the island by which it was found, the Antikythera Mechanism had been hidden in the ocean for over 20 centuries. This is a textbook example of how humans have been automating processes for thousands of years. This video offers an insightful juxtaposition of using modern computers to analyze ancient computers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/02-introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/02-introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be learning about historical computing machines. Now, computers like we know today with your electronic laptops and cell phones and everything aren&amp;rsquo;t just electronic, but really anything that can compute a value, whether it be mechanical, electrical, or even biological. What we&amp;rsquo;re looking at here is a piece of what is considered one of the oldest computing machines that we know of the Antikythera mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Computer (Pt. 1)</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/03-what-is-a-computer-pt1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/03-what-is-a-computer-pt1/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script Now that we have an understanding of the resources available at the time, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back and think about what it would be like to be an inventor in let&amp;rsquo;s say the 1600s for a minute. If you wanted to design a machine that would aid in the computation of complex values, what should it do? What does that mean for a computer?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charles Babbage and His Difference Engine #2</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/04-difference-engine/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/04-difference-engine/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Notes About This Selection While the creation on Babbage&amp;rsquo;s Difference Engine #2 was turned down by the government, we get to see this machine which was built in modern times. Babbage had a small prototype which he would demonstrate for party guests and it was clear to those who saw it, that Babbage was incredibly talented and intelligent. This is further proven by the prototype&amp;rsquo;s modern counterpart. It is astonishing that it was created with such precision using just pencils and paper!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How an 1803 Jacquard Loom Led to Computer Technology</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/05-jacquard-loom/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/05-jacquard-loom/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Notes About This Selection In this video, we get to see another example of antique computers! Created in 1803, the Jacquard loom used technology that would be a predecessor to the more modern punch cards and in turn, modern computers. As before with the difference engine and the Antikythera mechanism, this was a result of humans trying to automate tasks which required a lot of precision.
Reference The Henry Ford.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Computer (Pt. 2)</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/06-what-is-a-computer-pt2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/06-what-is-a-computer-pt2/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Resources Slides Video Script So now that we have the capability of computing values without human error, once we have that ability, the next important part of the computer is to accept variable input from the user. And as I mentioned before, it&amp;rsquo;s not just the fact that we can input numbers into the computer. But, what if we could actually reprogram the device? Right? What if we could enable certain features or certain abilities of that computer by just pushing the input?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Computing: Crash Course Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/07-early-computing-crash-course/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cs-zero/i-concepts/02-early-computing-machines/07-early-computing-crash-course/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Notes About This Selection This video gives a great insight into what we will cover in this course. Our journey will start with early computation tools, such as the abacus, slide rules, and astrolabe! We see punch cards as a connection between early computing and modern computing.
Reference CrashCourse. &amp;ldquo;Early Computing: Crash Course Computer Science&amp;rdquo;. Feb, 22, 2017. YouTube. Available: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O5nskjZ_GoI</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>