<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Search and Information Retrieval :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 12:25:42 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Relational Data</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/01-relational/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/01-relational/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at information retrieval. But before we get to that point, we need to start talking about databases and how data is actually stored. So for this example, we’re going to be working on our own social network called K-Stater. Specifically, we’ve been asked to help design a way to keep track of all the data on a site, like a social network, like K-Stater should have. So if you take a few minutes and brainstorm what kind of data or imagine what kind of information we may need, for example, of course, we’ll need to have some sort of way to track our users like maybe your eID, name, birthday, major, and maybe even just your phone number. And, you know, of course, we’ll need a lot of other information to make a full website like this work. But we can start off with the basics right, just keeping track of our users. But since we want to keep track of all that information, we need some way to actually store it. And so there’s tons of different ways that we could actually store that on our computers, right, of how our computer systems are designed to store information in that way.</description></item><item><title>Searching the Web</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/02-searching-web/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/02-searching-web/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script So in this video, we’re going to reiterate a little bit what we talked about with our relational database, right? Because the whole point of the relational database is that we can store lots of information in a very structured way that is easily searchable. That’s really important in today’s world, because we have the World Wide Web, right, the internet, it’s huge. Now that we know how to store data in a reasonable fashion, we have to talk about where most of the data in the world is actually stored. And for that, really is just the internet. So at the highest level, right, we can think of the internet as a very big, very big, completely unstructured database of all of the information in the world, right, because pretty much almost everything is connected to the internet anymore. Not everything, but pretty much. Some parts of it are very structured, and very well formed and easily searchable. But generally, it will never be as well structured as we’d like. And one structure might be entirely different than another. And so it’s not going to be very uniform across the entire internet. However, we are pretty much constantly using tools like Google to find information and the vast amount of data that is out there on the web, and it does a pretty good job, doesn’t it? When you do a Google search most of the time you find what you’re looking for. So how do we go about finding information in a big giant unstructured pile of data that really is pretty much like finding a needle in a haystack, as far as Internet is concerned. So that task is the job of information retrieval specialist, and the algorithms and research they do. In a base form, right, let’s say we want to find some information on a very simple Internet, maybe this is back in the early early, early days, where there was pretty much nothing out there.</description></item><item><title>The Internet: How Search Works</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/03-how-search/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/03-how-search/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Page Rank</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/04-ranking/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/04-ranking/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back. In this video, we’re going to be taking a deeper look into what kind of queries we can actually ask of Google or searching the web. So we’ve already looked at simple queries like cat, dog, or cat and dog, or cat or dog. But that’s really not as interesting of a question to ask of the internet, right? When we’re wanting to find all of the webpages that are about cats, not just have the occurrences of the word cat, but are about cats. And so how do you know which web pages are more likely to be about cats and webpages that are more likely to be about dogs? And how could you tell the difference? And how would you modify our search algorithm that we had talked about earlier to account for that. So this ranking of the internet becomes a little bit more complicated than our simple straight up text queries.</description></item><item><title>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 3 - Page Rank</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/05-9algs-ch3/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/05-9algs-ch3/index.html</guid><description>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 3 - Page Rank</description></item><item><title>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 8 - Databases</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/06-9algs-ch8/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/19-search-info/06-9algs-ch8/index.html</guid><description>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 8 - Databases</description></item></channel></rss>