<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cryptography :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:02:51 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/01-intro/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/01-intro/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script In this module, we’re going to take a look at one of the most important applications of computer science and modern technology- the field of cryptography. Cryptography is the study of ways to communicate securely and privately in the presence of third parties. If you think about it, cryptography is very important today with the rise of the Internet and modern technology. Any data that’s transmitted over the internet can be intercepted by just about anyone from your internet service provider all the way to the website that you’re communicating with, and anybody in between. Remember, the internet is built upon open standards, and so anybody can understand the packet formats and deconstruct them very quickly. So we need a way that we can encrypt and secure the data inside of those packets. So they can only be opened by the intended recipients, and that’s where the field of cryptography comes in. There were lots of historical Computer Science professionals interested in cryptography. Charles Babbage was very fascinated by it. Alan Turing was especially involved in cryptography, and Claude Shannon, were all involved in the field of cryptography. Also, surprisingly, the author Edgar Allan Poe was one of the people that was really excited about cryptography outside of computer scientists, and in fact, helped popularize cryptography as a word game that you might see in your newspaper.</description></item><item><title>Enigma Machine (Part 1)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/02-enigma-intro/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/02-enigma-intro/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script In this module, we’re going to take a look at one great example of the use of cryptography in computer science. And to do that we have to go all the way back in history to look at World War Two. This slide right here shows the height of German occupation of Europe during World War Two. And during that time, the Germans were sending encrypted messages to all of their field commanders using a system that was very, very much thought to be uncrackable at that time. So we’re going to take a look at what that system is, how it works, and how the Allies were actually able to crack it by taking advantage of some of the knowledge that they had about such a system. Oh, and of course, some of this information would have been very much top secret, and a lot of it was classified up until just a few decades ago. So it’s really an interesting time to take a look back at what was going on during World War Two, and take a look at how the Germans were able to build a very interesting encryption system that was then later broken by the allies. So let’s start by taking a look at a quick video demonstrating the German’s Enigma machine and how it worked.</description></item><item><title>Enigma Machine - Numberphile</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/03-enigma-machine/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/03-enigma-machine/index.html</guid><description>Watch through 5:50</description></item><item><title>Enigma Machine (Part 2)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/04-enigma/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/04-enigma/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script I present to you the German Enigma machine. The Enigma machine was used to encode messages during World War Two. And it was a really interesting piece of equipment. It used several different rotors that were rotated to create a key for the encryption, and used a plug board and a keyboard for inputs. And so as we saw in the video with the Enigma machine, you would set the rotors to a particular key. And then when you press the key on the keyboard, and electrical current would go from that key, through the plug board, through the rotors, back out through the rotors, and then light up a lamp above. And so by pressing that key and holding it down, it would show you the letter that that letter should be encrypted to. Then, you would press the next key, another letter would light up, you press another key, another letter would light up. And each time you press a key, the rotors would advance one click changing the way that things were encrypted. And so of course, if you sat there and kept pressing the same key on the keyboard, you would notice that every single time you did that the letters that it would light up would be different every single time making you think that this is a very, very hard to break cipher. And indeed it was.</description></item><item><title>Flaw in the Enigma Code - Numberphile</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/05-flaw-enigma/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/05-flaw-enigma/index.html</guid><description>Watch through 2:40</description></item><item><title>Cracking Enigma</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/06-cracking-enigma/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/06-cracking-enigma/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script The success for cracking the Enigma machine really comes down to the work of this man, Marian Rejewski. Marian Rejewski was a Polish mathematician who worked on the Enigma machine in the early days of the 1920s and 1930s. The Enigma machine was actually originally available as a corporate machine; you could go out and buy it as a corporation, and use it to encrypt and store data. And so it wasn’t until much later that was taken over by the German Nazi Party and used in their war efforts. And so public Enigma machines were available and could be studied. And so Marian Rejewski was able to study some of the early Enigma machines and try and predict the adaptations that Germany made as they move closer to war in the late 1920s and 30s. So based on his work, he was able to determine what the Germans were doing and was even able to eventually replicate some of the German machines that they had created. But of course, that was just part of the story. So to crack the Enigma machine, it was really first cracked by Marian Rejewski of Poland. He was able to use some of those publicly available Enigma machines to crack some of the earliest things that they did. By 1938, as Germany was getting closer to war, they added two new wheels of their own making it much much harder to crack if you didn’t know the wheels existed. And so Marian Rejewski of Poland contacted folks in England and gave them a lot of his research and ask them for assistance. And so by 1939, Alan Turing, working together with the folks at Bletchley Park, created what he called the Bombe, which was a machine that could decrypt the Enigma machine. And so work on the Bombe progressed pretty much throughout the entire war. And by 1945, almost every single message that the German sent using the Enigma machine, could be deciphered by the allies within two days. So what is the Bombe? The Bombe is a machine developed by Alan Turing to simulate hundreds of Enigma machines side by side. You can see that it has all of these sets of three wheels, simulating the three wheels that might be present in an Enigma machine. And it was designed to explore many of the weaknesses and other facts about the Enigma machine that were known to the Allies based on the work of Marian Rejewski and Alan Turing at that particular time. So let’s take a look at a quick video of a Bombe in action just to see what it looks like.</description></item><item><title>Bombe Demonstration at Bletchley Park</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/07-bombe/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/07-bombe/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modern Cryptography</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/08-modern-crypto/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/08-modern-crypto/index.html</guid><description>Resources Slides Video Script Of course, the impact of cracking the Enigma machine cannot be understated. It’s probably best put by Sir Harry Hensley, who is a British intelligence historian. And he wrote, “My own conclusion is that it shortened the war by not less than two years and probably by four years … we wouldn’t have in fact been able to do the Normandy landings, even if we had left the Mediterranean aside, until at the earliest 1946, probably a bit later.” So really, the ability of the Allies to decrypt and decode the German messages sent via the Enigma machine was really important toward ending the war effort. And it’s almost unfathomable to imagine how bad World War Two had been, had it gone on for two or even four more years. And, of course, this is just focusing on the work in the European Theater. There was also another program called Ultra. It was based in the Pacific Theater, focused on decrypting some of the Japanese messages that were sent during World War Two. And so later on, we may add some videos to this module discussing that program, as well.</description></item><item><title>Public Key Cryptography: Diffie-Hellman Key Exchange (short version)</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/09-diffie-hellman/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/09-diffie-hellman/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>RSA Encryption</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/10-rsa/index.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/10-rsa/index.html</guid><description>Error in Video In the video, the values of d and e are swapped at one point. Thankfully, this doesn’t matter since they are commutative and can be used in any order, but it is a bit confusing. We’ll correct this video in the future!
Resources Slides RSA Calculator Worksheet Video Script Let’s take a look at one modern form of encryption called RSA encryption. RSA was developed in 1977, and it was named for the three creators- Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir, and Leonard Adelman. RSA encryption uses the product of two large prime numbers to generate a key that’s used to encrypt data, and the strength of the key really depends on the difficulty of factoring that large number back into its two prime numbers. So for example, if we say our key number is 1071. Can we factor that into the two prime numbers? We could do it eventually, but we’d have to check a lot of different numbers to see what it was. So now imagine that 1071, instead of being a number with just four digits, was a number that had 64 digits in it. That’s really the size of the prime number products that we’re talking about when we do RSA encryption. And so really, the key to RSA encryption is the fact that it’s very, very difficult to factor a large number like that into the two unique prime numbers that are used to create it. So let’s take a look at how RSA encryption works to see why that’s important and why it can create a system that is easily broken if that rule doesn’t hold.</description></item><item><title>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 4 - Public Key Cryptography</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/11-9algs-ch4/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/11-9algs-ch4/index.html</guid><description>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 4 - Public Key Cryptography</description></item><item><title>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 9 - Digital Signatures</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/12-9algs-ch9/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 16:27:26 -0500</pubDate><author>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</author><guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/iii-topics/16-cryptography/12-9algs-ch9/index.html</guid><description>Nine Algorithms that Changed the Future Ch 9 - Digital Signatures</description></item></channel></rss>