<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Interactive Web :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/04-interactive-web/index.html</link><description>Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re gonna be taking a look at interactive web technologies. And now we’ve talked a lot about these things in the past about Web 1.0 vs 2.0. So going from the static plain HTML Web to Web 2.0, where everything is much more dynamic, interactive, more media, more content, more interactive technology. And so we’re going to take a look at how we can actually use some of these to make our websites a little bit more interesting. Some of the primary ones that we’ll be talking about today are the Document Object Model, which is fundamentally how a lot of the Web 2.0 pages actually are structured and work. JavaScript, Ajax, and JSON, which also helped make our webpages a lot more interactive. First, let’s take a look at the Document Object Model or DOM. So the document object model is really how a web page is actually structured. So you can kind of think of the window here as like a tab in your web browser. So the entire contents of that is your window. And in that window, we have history of that web page. So maybe even things like cookies, past searches, past form information, things like that, location information. But then we have the document itself, which is the actual page that we’ve loaded. So your document or HTML, everything that was between the open and close HTML tags, actually goes here.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/04-interactive-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>