<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tic Tac Toe JS :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/07-tictactoe-js/index.html</link><description>JQuery Script Tag In some older videos, the JQuery script tag is shown using http in the URL. This should be changed to https in order to work correctly due to some recent browser security updates. Alternatively, you can always find the correct JQuery script tag by visiting https://releases.jquery.com/ and clicking the “uncompressed” link next to the latest version of JQuery.
Resources Slides Video Script Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to start making our Tic Tac Toe game a little bit more interesting by enabling us to actually play the game. So a few pieces that we need before we actually start programming with the JavaScript. The first part is our script tag. So we need to actually embed JavaScript into our web page. So to do that, we’re going to add a couple tags, right after our table or our board that we had before. So down here towards the bottom right above your body tag, right underneath the table tag, we’re going to add our script tags. And these script tags are going to be used to import the JavaScript. So just like what we’ve done with our CSS up here, where our link tag is actually importing our CSS, our Cascading Style Sheets into our page. Our script tag is going to work very much the same. So I’m going to go ahead and just paste these in here. And then let’s go ahead and talk about them. So each script tag has a source attribute, where the source attribute is going to be the actual location of the script that you’re actually pulling in. And inside, typically, you won’t see one unless you’re importing JavaScript. Typically won’t see anything in between the opening and closing tag, but you could just leave the source blank, and actually put the JavaScript straight inside of the tag itself.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/ii-internet/13-webprog/07-tictactoe-js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>