<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CC 110 Syllabus - Spring 2022 :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/old/spring22/index.html</link><description>CC 110 - Introduction to Computing - Spring 2022 Instructor Contact Information Instructor: Emily Alfs-Votipka (emilyalfs AT ksu DOT edu)
I use she/her pronouns. Feel free to share your own pronouns with me, and I’ll do my best to use them! Office: DUE 2161 Virtual Office Hours: Schedule a meeting with me: https://calendly.com/emilyalfs Appointments held via Zoom. Preferred Methods of Communication: Email: Please use “cc110-help” (cc110-help@ksuemailprod.onmicrosoft.com if not on web-mail) for all communication regarding these courses as it allows instructors and TAs to provide a clear and detailed response, as well as easily store and record communication for reference later. You should receive a response within one business day, and hopefully much sooner. Note emailing the instructor or teaching assistants directly may result in longer wait times for your support. Teaching Assistants Undergraduate Teaching Assistants Name Office Hours (DUE 1118) Easton Bolinger M 4:30 - 6:00 Monday Zoom W: 1:30 - 3:30 Wednesday Zoom Chris Loura M, U: 2:30 - 5:00 Brandon Bednar T: 2:30 - 3:30, U: 12:30 - 2:00 Zoom Link for Both Prerequisites None Course Overview An overview of the history of computers and programming. Famous historical figures and their impact in modern computing. Introduction to major topics in computer science such as artificial intelligence, high performance computing, cryptography, big data, cyber security, robotics, and more. Brief experience with computer programming concepts.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/old/spring22/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>