<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CC 110 Syllabus - Fall 2025 :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-hs-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/index.html</link><description>Info This is the official syllabus for the concurrent enrollment version of this course. It is subject to change as we work on building our overall concurrent enrollment program. Any changes will be clearly communicated to all teachers and students.
Your teachers may give you a syllabus that includes additional information that is specific to your class.
CC 110 - Introduction to Computing HS (2025-2026) Instructor Contact Information Instructor: Russell Feldhausen (russfeld AT ksu DOT edu) Office: DUE 2213, but I mostly work remotely from Kansas City, MO Phone: (785) 292-3121 (Call/Text) Website: https://russfeld.me Virtual Office Hours: By appointment via Zoom. Schedule a meeting at https://calendly.com/russfeld Preferred Methods of Communication: High School Teacher: Students should primarily contact your high school teacher for any assistance in the course. Email: When contacting the K-State instructors, email is preferred. We will try to respond within one business day. Phone/Text: Emergencies only! We will do our best to respond as quickly as we can. Prerequisites None Course Overview An overview of the history of computers and programming. Famous historical figures and their impact in modern computing. Introduction to major topics in computer science such as artificial intelligence, high performance computing, cryptography, big data, cyber security, robotics, and more. Brief experience with computer programming concepts.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-hs-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>