<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CC 110 Syllabus - Fall 2023 :: Intro CS Textbook</title><link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/old/fall23/index.html</link><description>CC 110 - Introduction to Computing - Spring 2023 Instructor Contact Information Instructor: Safia Malallah I use she/her pronouns. Feel free to share your own pronouns with me, and I’ll do my best to use them! Email: Safia@ksu.edu and CC cc110-help@KSUemailProd.onmicrosoft.com>
Please avoid using the Canvas email functionality; instead, contact me directly at this email address. Canvas emails don’t always reach my inbox reliably.
I’d like to emphasize that I make an effort to respond to emails within 24 “business hours” (if you don’t receive a reply within 24 hours, please don’t hesitate to reach out again). Specifically, on Fridays, I can only respond until I need to attend to my kids, which means you can anticipate my reply on Monday. Therefore, it’s a good practice to reach out with your questions well in advance to ensure you have enough time to receive my response. Office: DUE 2161 Office Hours: safiamalallah.com/calendar Want to meet with me outside of my regular office hours? https://calendly.com/safiamalallah Preferred Methods of Communication: Email: Please use “cc110-help” (cc110-help@ksuemailprod.onmicrosoft.com if not on web-mail) for all communication regarding these courses as it allows instructors and TAs to provide a clear and detailed response, as well as easily store and record communication for reference later. You should receive a response within one business day, and hopefully much sooner. Note emailing the instructor or teaching assistants directly may result in longer wait times for your support. Undergraduate Teaching Assistants All TA office hours can be found on the embedded calendar below. TBA</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</managingEditor><webMaster>altcs@ksu.edu (K-State CS Faculty)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cs-zero/00-introduction/06-cc110-syllabus/old/fall23/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>